palringo.com 2009-02-04

# Palringo Vocal IM

## Overview

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. When you sign up for any of our services you will be deemed to have read and accepted this Privacy Policy and to have consented to the uses of your personal information as set out below. 

Palringo provides an innovative communications application and thus requires some information from you. In order to ensure the smooth operation of the service we will also automatically collect information about your usage of the service. We collect the information in order to offer the best service possible and we understand the importance of maintaining your personal privacy. The information we collect is held securely and will not be supplied to third parties except as specified in this Privacy Policy. 

  * Information
  * Security and Availability of Your Information Posted on Palringo
  * Sharing of your Information
  * Cookies
  * Using Your Personal Information in Other Countries
  * Location Based Services
  * Access to Your Information
  * Children
  * Other Websites
  * Changes to this Policy
  * Feedback

## Information

We limit the required personal information to those details required to offer an effective service, but give you the opportunity to supply further information that will be useful to us in better adapting the service to your needs. 

  * Personal Information: In addition to email and phone details, after you register you have the option to provide us with personal information which may include (but may not necessarily be limited to) your gender, age group, country, your likes/dislikes and other personal preferences. We use this information to deliver the service and communicate with you effectively and to learn about our customer base through abstract statistics (e.g. percentage of female users aged 18-22). 
  * Usage History: We collect information on usage of our service including details like number of messages sent, length of connection and usage of the offline messaging facility. This information is important as it allows us to monitor the performance and usage of the system. 
  * Support: If interested, you have the option to submit bug reports, feature requests, and other feedback to our development team. These and similar services in the future may require us to maintain your account name and password. 
  * Email Address: We ask for your email address in order to send you download instructions and to keep you updated of our status. 

Top

## Security and Availability of Your Information Posted on Palringo

We take many precautions to keep your personal information secure from unauthorized access, such as encrypted storage of personal information on our servers and internal corporate policies to limit access to systems that store your personal information. In addition, we keep the most sensitive information, such as your Personal Attributes/Interests, encrypted so it can only be accessed when authorised. We will periodically destroy old personal information when it is no longer required or as required by law. 

When using our service you can choose who you share your information with, for example through making your information only available in a private group. However, when using the Internet no security measures can be guaranteed at all times. We have no control over others to whom you make your information available. We cannot guarantee that your information will not be viewed by unauthorised persons. If you remove information it may still remain available to others who have previously had access to it and who may have copied it. 

You also need to be aware that your information may become available in the third party search engines results (Google, Yahoo, Ask for example). This should not ordinarily happen to information that is published by you in a private group but any information published in a public group may become generally available. We cannot and do not guarantee that third party search engine "crawlers" and "spiders" will not access and make publicly available your information, particularly if posted in a public group. You should also be aware that if information is published in a private group and the administrator of that private group changes the profile to a public group then all information previously posted in the private group will become generally available for anyone to see. 

Top

## Sharing of your Information

We will not sell, or rent your email address or any of your personal information. We will only use or share your personal information as we believe is necessary: 

  * to fulfil your requests and to communicate with you (for example for billing, collection and account verification purposes); 
  * to provide our service to you;
  * to enforce our Terms of Service;
  * to protect personal safety;
  * to comply with laws or respond to legal processes;
  * to allow for change of ownership in which case your information still remains protected under this Privacy Policy; 
  * to allow for advertising audits to validate the size and composition of the viewing audience; and 
  * as otherwise permitted and required by applicable law.

We may share your personal information with other companies in the Palringo group or with other carefully selected business partners with whom we have a trusted business relationship. We may we use your personal information to provide you with promotional information about new services and other services offered by us and our business partners. At any time, if you do not wish to continue receiving promotional information, you may notify us at [personalinfo@palringo.com](mailto:personalinfo@palringo.com) whereupon we shall cease sending promotional information to you. 

Top

## Cookies

We use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to the cookie file on your computer's hard drive. Cookies enable you to navigate around our website. Cookies do not obtain personal information about you or read any material kept on your computer. Cookies only identify your browser. You can set your web browser to disable cookies and you can also delete cookies that have previously been added to your cookie file. 

Top

## Using Your Personal Information in Other Countries

Your country's privacy laws may require your consent before your personal information can be exported to countries with weaker privacy laws. Our Terms of Service requires your consent to this practice, but regardless of where your information is processed, this Privacy Policy will remain in effect. 

Top

## Location Based Services

We collect your location data to allow you to publish your location and to provide you with relevant location based services that might be of value to you. Identifying your location is necessary for us to provide you with those location based services you request from us. We shall only provide our location based services to you if you expressly request us to do so. You agree that if you let others use location based services that you have asked us to provide to you or if you let others use your mobile handset or other terminal equipment, it is your responsibility to inform them that their location may be identified. 

Top

## Access to Your Information

You can access and update most of your personal information through the client software or our web site. If you wish to review and/or correct any other personal information not yet available through the client software, please send a request to [personalinfo@palringo.com](mailto:personalinfo@palringo.com). 

We may charge an administration fee to cover our costs in providing information following a request from you. 

Top

## Children

We will not register a child under the age of 13 (or such other age as may apply depending upon applicable laws where a child is located) for Palringo products or services without first obtaining a parent's or guardian's permission. 

We do not contact children under the age of 13 (or such other age as may apply depending upon applicable laws where a child is located) with promotional offers or for marketing purposes without a parent's or guardian's permission nor do we ask them for more personal information, as a condition of using our products or services, than is reasonably necessary for us to provide such products or services. 

Top

## Other Websites

We do not represent or warrant that any information that may be obtained through any link to or from our web site or service is accurate, complete or current. We do not accept any responsibility for any loss that may arise as a result of relying upon information obtained from another website. You are advised to read applicable terms and policies before use of any other website. 

Top

## Changes to this Policy

Our Privacy Policy may be updated periodically. Updates will take effect when posted on our website. 

Top

## Feedback

If you have any concerns, questions, or ideas on how we can improve the way we deal with your personal information, please let us know by emailing [personalinfo@palringo.com](mailto:personalinfo@palringo.com)

Top
